ENAME		Name	|	Description	|	Veggie Level
E100	|	Curcumin	|	An orange yellow colour derived from the root of the curcuma (turmeric) plant.	|	0
E101	|	Riboflavin	|	Also known as vitamin B2. It has a key role in maintaining health in humans and animals. 	|	0
E101	|	lactoflavin	|	E101	|	0
E101	|	Vitamin B2	|	E101	|	0
E101a	|	Riboflavin-5'-Phosphate	|	A more soluble form of Riboflavin (B2), sometimes used as an orange / red food color. Although naturally present in many foods such as milk, eggs, liver and vegetables, it is commercially prepared from yeasts and also manufactured synthetically. 	|	0
E101a	|	Flavin mononucleotide	|	E101a	|	0
E101a	|	FMN	|	E101a	|	0
E102	|	Tartrazine	|	A synthetic lemon-yellow food coloring	|	0
E102	|	FD&C Yellow	|	E102	|	0
E102	|	Acid Yelloe 23	|	E102	|	0
E102	|	Food Yellow 4	|	E102	|	0
E102	|	Trisodium1	|	E102	|	0
E103	|	Alkannin	|	A natural dye extracted from borage plants. 	|	0
E104	|	Quinoline Yellow WS	|	A synthetic dye used to color food.	|	0
E104	|	Quinoline Yellow 	|	E104	|	0
E104	|	Food Yellow 13	|	E104	|	0
E105	|	Fast Yellow AB	|	A sythetic dye now banned for use in food and drinks.	|	4
E106	|	Riboflavin-5-Sodium Phosphate	|	 Yellow food coloring; commercially prepared from yeasts or manufactured synthetically. 	|	1
E106	|	Flavin mononucleotide	|	E106	|	1
E107	|	Yellow 2G	|	A synthetic yellow dye, banned in Austria, Japan, Norway, Sweden, Switzerland and the US.	|	0
E107	|	Lissamine Fast Yellow	|	E107	|	0
E107	|	 Acid Yellow 17	|	E107	|	0
E107	|	 Food Yellow 5	|	E107	|	0
E107	|	Acid Leather Yellow 2GL	|	E107	|	0
E107	|	Fenalan Yellow G	|	E107	|	0
E107	|	Erio Flavine 3G	|	E107	|	0
E110	|	Sunset Yellow FCF	|	A synthetic 'coal tar' and azo yellow food dye. 	|	4
E110	|	Orange Yellow S	|	E110	|	4
E110	|	FD&C Yellow 6	|	E110	|	4
E111	|	Orange GGN	|	Former food dye now banned for use in food. 	|	0
E111	|	alpha-naphthol orange	|	E111	|	0
E120	|	Carmine	|	Bright red food, drink and cosmetic coloring made from crushed insects.	|	4
E120	|	Cochineal	|	E120	|	4
E120	|	Carminic acid	|	E120	|	4
E120	|	Natural Red4	|	E120	|	4
E120	|	Crimson Lake	|	E120	|	4
E121	|	Citrus Red 2	|	Food coloring only permitted for use to color the skins if oranges.	|	0
E121	|	SOlvent Red 80	|	E121	|	0
E122	|	Carmoisine	|	A synthetic red food coloring.	|	0
E122	|	Food Red 3,	|	E122	|	0
E122	|	Azorubin S,	|	E122	|	0
E122	|	Brillantcarmoisin O,	|	E122	|	0
E122	|	Acid Red 14	|	E122	|	0
E123	|	Amaranth	|	Red food coloring made from the amaranth plant.	|	0
E123	|	FD&C Red No. 2	|	E123	|	0
E123	|	C.I. Food Red 9	|	E123	|	0
E123	|	Acid Red 27	|	E123	|	0
E123	|	Azorubin S	|	E123	|	0
E124	|	Ponceau 4R	|	Red food coloring	|	0
E124	|	Cochineal Red A	|	E124	|	0
E124	|	C.I. Acid Red 18	|	E124	|	0
E124	|	Brilliant Scarlet	|	E124	|	0
E125	|	Scarlet GN	|	 Widely used red azo dye, usually synthesized from aromatic hydrocarbons from petroleum.	|	4
E125	|	Crimson 4R	|	E125	|	4
E125	|	Food Red 1	|	E125	|	4
E125	|	FD & C Red no. 4	|	E125	|	4
E125	|	Hexacol Ponceau SX	|	E125	|	4
E125	|	Maple Ponceau SX	|	E125	|	4
E125	|	Ponceau SX	|	E125	|	4
E125	|	Purple 4R	|	E125	|	4
E126	|	Ponceau 6R	|	Water soluble red food coloring	|	0
E126	|	Crystal ponceau 6R	|	E126	|	0
E126	|	Crystal scarlet	|	E126	|	0
E126	|	Brilliant crystal scarlet 6R	|	E126	|	0
E126	|	Acid Red 44	|	E126	|	0
E127	|	Erythrosine	|	Synthetic red, coal tar food coloring	|	0
E127	|	Red No. 3	|	E127	|	0
E128	|	Red 2G	|	A red synthetic coal tar or azo dye used mainly in cooked meat products.	|	0
E128	|	Acid Red 1	|	E128	|	0
E128	|	Food Red 10	|	E128	|	0
E128	|	Amidonaphthol red G	|	E128	|	0
E128	|	azogeranine	|	E128	|	0
E128	|	azophloxine	|	E128	|	0
E128	|	azofloxin	|	E128	|	0
E129	|	Allura Red AC	|	Orange-red food coloring.	|	0
E129	|	Food Red 17	|	E129	|	0
E129	|	 FD&C Red 40	|	E129	|	0
E130	|	Indanthrene blue RS	|	An organic dye used for painting.	|	0
E130	|	C.I. vat blue 4	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	carbon paper blue	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	 blue O	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	carbanthrene blue 2R	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	fenan blue RSN	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	graphtol blue RL	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	medium blue	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	monolite fast blue 3R	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	indanthrene	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	indanthrone	|	E130	|	0
E130	|	pigment blue 60	|	E130	|	0
E131	|	Patent Blue V	|	A dark bluish-violet synthetic coal tar dye.	|	0
E131	|	 Food Blue 5	|	E131	|	0
E131	|	Sulphan Blue	|	E131	|	0
E131	|	Acid Blue 3	|	E131	|	0
E132	|	Indigo carmine	|	A blue synthetic coal tar dye.	|	0
E132	|	indigotine	|	E132	|	0
E132	|	5,5'-indigodisulfonic acid sodium salt	|	E132	|	0
E133	|	Brilliant Blue FCF	|	Blue coloring used for food and cosmetics.	|	0
E133	|	FD&C Blue No.1	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Acid Blue 9	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	D&C Blue No. 4	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Alzen Food Blue No. 1	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Atracid Blue FG	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Erioglaucine	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Eriosky blue	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Patent Blue AR	|	E133	|	0
E133	|	Xylene Blue VSG	|	E133	|	0
E140	|	Chlorophylls	|	Natural, plant-based green food coloring.	|	0
E140	|	Chlorophyllins	|	E140	|	0
E141	|	Copper complexes of chlorophylls and chlorophyllins	|	Natural, plant derived green food coloring.	|	0
E141	|	 Copper complexes of chlorophylls	|	E414	|	0
E141	|	 Copper complexes of chlorophyllins	|	E414	|	0
E142	|	Green S	|	A green synthetic coal tar dye used to color food.	|	0
E142	|	FD&C Green 4	|	E142	|	0
E142	|	Acid green 50	|	E142	|	0
E142	|	Lissamine Green B	|	E142	|	0
E142	|	Wool Green S	|	E142	|	0
E143	|	Fast Green FCF 	|	Green food dye banned in many countries.	|	4
E143	|	Food green 3	|	E143	|	4
E143	|	Green 1724	|	E143	|	4
E143	|	Solid Green FCF	|	E143	|	4
E150a	|	Plain caramel	|	Dark brown to black food colorings, made by controlled heat treatment of sugar beet, maize starch, or sugar cane.	|	0
E150a	|	caustic caramel	|	E150a	|	0
E150a	|	spirit caramel	|	E150a	|	0
E150b	|	Caustic sulphite caramel	|		|	0
E150c	|	Ammonia caramel	|	Dark brown to black food colorings, made by controlled heat treatment of sugar beet, maize starch, or sugar cane.	|	0
E150c	|	baker's caramel	|	E150c	|	0
E150c	|	confectioner's caramel	|	E150c	|	0
E150c	|	beer caramel	|	E150c	|	0
E150d	|	Sulphite ammonia caramel	|	Caramel color, one of the oldest and most widely-used food colorings.	|	0
E150d	|	acid-proof caramel	|	E150d	|	0
E150d	|	soft-drink caramel	|	E150d	|	0
E151	|	Black PN	|	A violet/black synthetic coal tar and azo dye used in food.	|	0
E151	|	C.I. Food Black 1	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Blue Black BN	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Brilliant Acid Black	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Certicol Black PNW	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Brilliant Black BN	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Edicol Supra Black BN	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Hexacol Black PN	|	E151	|	0
E151	|	Naphthol Black	|	E151	|	0
E152	|	Carbon black	|	Banned for food use since 1984.	|	4
E152	|	Food Black 2	|	E152	|	4
E152	|	Black 7984	|	E152	|	4
E153	|	Vegetable carbon	|	Natural element, produced by burning vegetable matter.	|	0
E154	|	Brown FK	|	A combination of synthetic azo dyes used mainly to color fish products.	|	0
E154	|	Kipper Brown	|	E154	|	0
E154	|	Chocolate Brown FK	|	E154	|	0
E154	|	 C.I. Food Brown 1	|	E154	|	0
E155	|	Brown HT	|	Synthetic (coal tar / azo) brown food coloring.	|	0
E155	|	 Chocolate Brown HT	|	E155	|	0
E155	|	Food Brown 3	|	E155	|	0
E160a	|	Alpha-carotene	|	Commonly derived from yellow-orange, or dark-green vegetables.	|	0
E160a	|	Beta-carotene	|	E160a	|	0
E160a	|	Gamma-carotene	|	E160a	|	0
E160b	|	Annatto	|	Natural red to brown food coloring isolated from the seeds of the annatto tree.	|	0
E160b	|	Bixin	|	E160b	|	0
E160b	|	Norbixin	|	E160b	|	0
E160c	|	Paprika oleoresin	|	Natural colour isolated from the bell pepper.	|	0
E160c	|	Capsanthin	|	E160c	|	0
E160c	|	Capsorubin	|	E160c	|	0
E160d	|	Lycopene	|	Natural color isolated from tomatoes. 	|	0
E160e	|	Apocarotenal	|	Natural color, present in many plants.	|	0
E160e	|	 Food Orange 6	|	E160e	|	0
E160f	|	Food orange 7	|	Natural color, present in many plants. 	|	0
E161a	|	Flavoxanthin	|	Natural, rarely used yellow food coloring present in many plants.	|	0
E161b	|	Lutein	|	Natural, rarely used food yellow food color, present in many plants.	|	0
E161c	|	Cryptoxanthin	|	Natural color, present in many plants.	|	0
E161c	|	Cryptoxanthol	|	W161c	|	0
E161d	|	Rubixanthin	|	Natural yellow food color, present in many plants.	|	0
E161d	|	Natural yellow 27	|	E161d	|	0
E161e	|	Violaxanthin	|	Natural color, present in many plants.	|	0
E161f	|	Rhodoxanthin	|	Natural color prepared from different plant species.	|	0
E161g	|	Canthaxanthin	|	Widely used in food and also in tanning pills.	|	4
E161g	|	Cantaxanthine	|	E161g	|	4
E161g	|	Canthaxanthine	|	E161g	|	4
E161g	|	Lucantin red	|	E161g	|	4
E161g	|	Lucantin Red CWD	|	E161g	|	4
E161g	|	Carophyll Red 	|	E161g	|	4
E161g	|	Roxanthin Red 10	|	E161g	|	4
E161g	|	Food Orange 8	|	E161g	|	4
E161h	|	Zeaxanthin	|	Natural colour, prepared from several dried plants species. 	|	0
E161i	|	Citranaxanthin	|	 Generally prepared synthetically for use as an animal feed additive to impart a yellow color to chicken fat and egg yolks.	|	0
E161j	|	Astaxanthin	|	A powerful antioxidant used as a coloring agent.	|	3
E162	|	Betanin	|	Natural color commercially prepared from beetroot. 	|	0
E162	|	Beetroot Red	|	E162	|	0
E163	|	Anthocyanins	|	Natural water soluble plant pigments used to color foods and beverages.	|	0
E163	|	anthocyans	|	E163	|	0
E164	|	Saffron	|	A spice derived from the flower of Crocus sativus.	|	0
"E170"	|	"Calcium carbonate"	|	"White color for surface coating; anti-caking agent, filling agent, stabiliser in canned fruit. Also known as a chalk. "	|	0
"E170"	|	"Chalk"	|	E170	|	0
E171	|	"Titanium dioxide"	|	"Natural white mineral used for surface coating, to separate layers in products, and as a whitening agent in toothpaste."	|	0
E171	|	"Titania"	|	E171	|	0
E171	|	"Rutile"	|	E171	|	0
E171	|	"Anatase"	|	E171	|	0
E171	|	"Brookite"	|	E171	|	0
E172	|	"Iron oxide"	|	"Natural mineral commercially made from iron powder and used only for surface coating"	|	0
E172	|	"iron hydroxides"	|	E172	|	0
E173	|	"Aluminium"	|	"Natural metal with a silver grey color used for surface coating"	|	0
E173	|	"aluminum"	|	E173	|	0
E174	|	"Silver"	|	"Natural metal. Silver grey colour. Only used for surface coating."	|	0
E174	|	"Ag"	|	E174	|	0
E175	|	"Gold"	|	"Natural metal. Golden colour. Only used for surface coating."	|	0
E180	|	"Lithol Rubine BK"	|	"Synthetic red azo color containing aluminium and calcium ions and used for surface coating of cheese."	|	0
E180	|	"Pigment Rubine"	|	E180	|	0
E180	|	"Carmine 6B"	|	E180	|	0
E180	|	"Brilliant Carmine 6B"	|	E180	|	0
E180	|	"Permanent Rubin L6B"	|	E180	|	0
E180	|	"Latolrubine"	|	E180	|	0
E180	|	"Litholrubine"	|	E180	|	0
E181	|	"Tannin"	|	"Yellow-white color mainly used as flavoring in butter or nut flavors."	|	0
E181	|	"Acidum tannicum"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Gallotannic acid"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Digallic acid"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Gallotannin"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Tannimum"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Quercitannin"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Oak bark tannin"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Quercotannic acid"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Querci-tannic acid"	|	E181	|	0
E181	|	"Querco-tannic acid"	|	E181	|	0
E182	|	"Orcein"	|	"Dyes extracted from various species of lichen, also known as "orchella weeds"."	|	0
E182	|	"Orchill"	|	E182	|	0
E182	|	"Archil"	|	E182	|	0
E182	|	"Lacmus"	|	E182	|	0
E182	|	"Natural RED 28"	|	E182	|	0
E200	|	"Sorbic acid"	|	"A preservative, mainly against fungi and yeasts and used in a wide range of products."	|	0
E201	|	"Sodium sorbate"	|	"A preservative, used mainly against fungi and yeasts."	|	0
E202	|	"Potassium sorbate"	|	"This is a preservative, mainly against fungi and yeasts. It is not effective against bacteria."	|	0
E202	|	"Sorbistat potassium"	|	E202	|	0
E203	|	"Calcium sorbate"	|	"The calcium salt of sorbic acid, commonly used as a food preservative."	|	0
E209	|	"Heptylparaben"	|	"A preservative."	|	0
E210	|	"Benzoic acid"	|	"Synthetically produced antibacterial and antifungal preservative found in a wide range of foods."	|	0
E210	|	"Carboxybenzene"	|	E210	|	0
E210	|	"Dracylic acid"	|	E210	|	0
E211	|	"Sodium benzoate"	|	"Used as an antibacterial and antifungal preservative; as an antiseptic; and to disguise the taste of poor quality food."	|	0
E211	|	"benzoate of soda"	|	E211	|	0
E212	|	"Potassium benzoate"	|	Used in food as an antibacterial and antifungal preservative.	|	0
E212	|	"Benzoic acid"	|	E212	|	0
E212	|	"potassium salt"	|	E212	|	0
E213	|	"Calcium benzoate"	|	"Used as an antibacterial and antifungal preservative."	|	0
E213	|	"calcium salt"	|	E213	|	0
E213	|	"Benzoic acid"	|	E213	|	0
E214	|	"Ethylparaben"	|	"Food additive used as an antifungal preservative."	|	0
E214	|	"Ethyl paraben"	|	E214	|	0
E215	|	"Ethyl-p-hydroxybenzoate sodium salt"	|	"Used as an antifungal preservative."	|	0
E216	|	"Propylparaben (propyl para-hydroxybenzoate)"	|	"Manufactured synthetically for use in cosmetics, pharmaceuticals and foods."	|	0
E216	|	"propyl paraben"	|	E216	|	0
E217	|	"Sodium propyl para-hydroxybenzoate"	|	"Synthetically manufactured preservative used in cosmetics, pharmaceuticals and foods."	|	0
E218	|	"Methylparaben"	|	"Naturally derived anti-fungal preservative used in food, cosmetics, and personal care products."	|	0
E218	|	"Methyl paraben"	|	E218	|	0
E218	|	"Methyl p-hydroxybenzoate"	|	E218	|	0
E218	|	"Nipagin M"	|	E218	|	0
E218	|	"Tegosept"	|	E218	|	0
E218	|	"Mycocten"	|	E218	|	0
E219	|	"Sodium methyl para-hydroxybenzoate"	|	"Sodium salt of methylparaben used as a preservative."	|	0
E219	|	"Sodium methyl p-hydroxybenzoate"	|	E219	|	0
E219	|	"Methylparaben sodium salt"	|	E219	|	0
E219	|	"Sodium methylparaben"	|	E219	|	0
E220	|	"Sulphur dioxide"	|	"A preservative derived from coal tar."	|	0
E220	|	"Sulfurous anhydride"	|	E220	|	0
E221	|	"Sodium sulphite"	|	"Preservative used as a decontaminating agent in fresh orange juice, and during sugar refining."	|	0
E221	|	"Hypo clear"	|	E221	|	0
E222	|	"Sodium bisulfite"	|	"Chemical preservative."	|	0
E222	|	"Sodium hydrogen sulfite"	|	E222	|	0
E223	|	"Sodium metabisulphite"	|	"Inorganic chemical compound used in food as a preservative and antioxidant."	|	0
E223	|	"Sodium pyrosulfite"	|	E223	|	0
E223	|	"Sodium disulfite"	|	E223	|	0
E224	|	"Potassium metabisulphite"	|	"A white, non-stable powder, which reacts with oxygen to form potassium sulphate. It is used as a preservative and antioxidant, and sometimes also as a bleaching agent."	|	0
E224	|	"Potassium pyrosulfite"	|	E224	|	0
E224	|	"Dipotassium disulfite"	|	E224	|	0
E225	|	"Potassium sulphite"	|	"A food additive used as a preservative."	|	0
E226	|	"Calcium sulphite"	|	"A white, non-stable powder, which reacts with oxygen to form calcium sulphate. Used as a preservative, a firming agent, and may be used as a bleaching agent."	|	0
E226	|	"Sulfurous acid"	|	E226	|	0
E226	|	"calcium salt"	|	E226	|	0
E227	|	"Calcium hydrogen sulphite"	|	"It is a greenish fluid, which reacts to form calcium sulphite and is used as a preservative and firming agent."	|	0
E227	|	"Calcium bisulphite"	|	E227	|	0
E228	|	"Potassium hydrogen sulphite"	|	"It is a white, non-stable powder, which reacts with oxygen to form potassium sulphate and is used as a preservative."	|	0
E228	|	"Potassium bisulfite"	|	E228	|	0
E228	|	"potassium bisulphite solution"	|	E228	|	0
E228	|	"sulfurous acid"	|	E228	|	0
E228	|	"monopotassium salt"	|	E228	|	0
E228	|	"monopotassium sulfite"	|	E228	|	0
E230	|	"Diphenyl"	|	"An organic compound used as a disinfectant and preservative."	|	0
E231	|	"Orthophenyl phenol"	|	"Anti fungal agent used for agricultural purposes.Also used as a preservative and disinfectant."	|	0
E231	|	"o-phenylphenol"	|	E231	|	0
E231	|	"biphenylol"	|	E231	|	0
E231	|	"2-hydroxybiphenyl"	|	E231	|	0
E231	|	"orthophenyl phenol"	|	E231	|	0
E231	|	"o-xenol"	|	E231	|	0
E231	|	"orthoxenol"	|	E231	|	0
E232	|	"Sodium orthophenyl phenol"	|	"Preservative used on citrus fruits to prevent post harvest diseases, during ripening, storage and transport."	|	0
E232	|	"sodium salt"	|	E232	|	0
E232	|	"2-Hydroxydiphenyl sodium"	|	E232	|	0
E232	|	"o-Phenylphenol sodium"	|	E232	|	0
E232	|	"o-Phenylphenol"	|	E232	|	0
E232	|	"Sodium o-phenylphenol"	|	E232	|	0
E232	|	"Sodium 2-phenylphenolate"	|	E232	|	0
E232	|	"sodium"	|	E232	|	0
E233	|	"Thiabendazole"	|	"A systemic benzimidazole fungicide used to control fruit and vegetable diseases such as mould, rot, blight, and stain, and to treat roundworms in humans and animals."	|	0
E233	|	"TBZ"	|	E233	|	0
E233	|	"thiabendazole"	|	E233	|	0
E233	|	"Mintezol"	|	E233	|	0
E233	|	"Tresaderm"	|	E233	|	0
E233	|	"Arbotect"	|	E233	|	0
E234	|	"Nisin"	|	"A natural antimicrobial agent, derived from controlled fermentation of the naturally occurring bacteria Streptococcus lactis, found in milk."	|	2
E235	|	"Pimaracin"	|	"An antimyotic food additive used to protect cheese from mould and yeast growth."	|	0
E235	|	"Natamycin"	|	E235	|	0
E236	|	"Formic acid"	|	"A preservative naturally found in the defense mechanism of ants bees and wasps - the sting"	|	4
E236	|	"ethanoic acid"	|	E236	|	4
E237	|	"Sodium formate"	|	"Preservative made from formic acid and sodium salt. Used in dyeing, printing of fabric, leather tanning, chrome electroplating process, paper industry as anti oxidants, enzyme stabiliser in detergents, as a fixing agent and in the manufacturing of Formic acid, Oxalic acid, Sodium hydro sulphite and metal formates."	|	4
E237	|	"formic acid"	|	E237	|	4
E237	|	"sodium salt"	|	E237	|	4
E238	|	"Calcium formate"	|	"The calcium salt of formic acid, which occurs naturally in stinging nettles, and in the stings and bites of many insects. Used as a preservative and antibacterial agent to help prevent spoilage in food."	|	0
E238	|	"formic acid calcium salt"	|	E238	|	0
E238	|	"calcoform"	|	E238	|	0
E239	|	"Hexamethylenetetramine"	|	"Produced from a reaction of ammonia with formaldehyde, and used as a preservative against fungi in food products."	|	0
E239	|	"Hexamine"	|	E239	|	0
E239	|	"Methenamine"	|	E239	|	0
E239	|	"Urotropine"	|	E239	|	0
E239	|	"Formin"	|	E239	|	0
E239	|	"Aminoform"	|	E239	|	0
E240	|	"Formaldehyde"	|	"Produced from the oxidation of methanol."	|	4
E240	|	"Methyl aldehyde"	|	E240	|	4
E240	|	"Methylene glycol"	|	E240	|	4
E240	|	"Methylene oxide"	|	E240	|	4
E240	|	"Formalin"	|	E240	|	4
E240	|	"Formol"	|	E240	|	4
E242	|	"Dimethyl dicarbonate"	|	"Used as a preservative and "cold sterilisant.""	|	0
E242	|	"DMDC"	|		|	0
E242	|	"Dicarbonic acid dimethyl ester"	|		|	0
E242	|	"Dimethyl pyrocarbonate"	|		|	0
E242	|	"Velcorin"	|		|	0
E249	|	"Potassium nitrite"	|	"A colour fixing and curing agent for meat. Nitrites can effect the body's ability to carry oxygen, resulting in shortness of breath, dizziness and headaches, nausea and vomiting."	|	
E250	|	"Sodium nitrite"	|	"Used for curing(preserving) meat and fish products"	|	0
E251	|	"Sodium nitrate"	|	"Sodium nitrate is a salt used extensively as a preservative and colour fixative of processed meats such as sausage and bacon."	|	0
E252	|	"Potassium nitrate"	|	"May be derived from waste animal or vegetable matter. Used in the preservation of meat products, such as, cured meats, bacon, ham, tongue, sausages, smoked frankfurters, pressed and tinned meats such as corned beef and some Dutch cheeses"	|	4
E252	|	"Saltpetre"	|	E252	|	4
E252	|	"Nitrate of potash"	|	E252	|	4
E260	|	"Acetic acid"	|	"Vinegar can be made from any liquid that is capable of being converted into alcohol in a two stage process. During fermentation the sugar in the liquid is converted into alcohol and carbon dioxide gas by the actions of yeast enzymes. Then, the alcohol combines with atmospheric oxygen by the action of the Acetobacter bacteria, forming acetic acid and water."	|	0
E261	|	"Potassium acetate"	|	"Potassium salt of acetic acid, an natural acid, present in most fruits. Produced by bacterial fermentation and thus present in all fermented products. Commercially produced by bacterial fermentation of sugar, molasses or alcohol or by chemical synthesis from acetealdehyde."	|	0
E261	|	"Potassium salt"	|	E261	|	0
E262	|	"Sodium acetates"	|	"Sodium acetate may be added to foods as a seasoning. It may be used in the form of sodium diacetate — a 1:1 complex of sodium acetate and acetic acid, given the E-number E262.Typical use in food products include bouillon's. Used as a preservative in liquorice, as a pickling agent and as a flavour-enhancing additive in meat and poultry. A frequent use is to impart a salt and vinegar flavour to potato crisps	|	0
E262	|	"Hot ice"	|	E262	|	0
E263	|	"Calcium acetate"	|	"An acidity regulator.A by product in the manufacture of wood alcohol. Used to make acetic acid (vinegar), to control the acidity of food during processing, as a thickening agent in cake mixes, packet desserts and puddings, a calcium supplement in pet foods, and as a preservative against microbial growth."	|	0
E263	|	"Acetate of lime"	|	E263	|	0
E263	|	"Calcium ethanoate"	|	E263	|	0
E263	|	"Calcium diacetate"	|	E263	|	0
E264	|	"Ammonium acetate"	|	"Ammonium acetate is the ammonium salt of acetic acid. It is a natural acid produced by bacterial fermentation"	|	0
E265	|	"Dehydroacetic acid"	|	"Organic compound. The compound is classified as a pyrone derivative and is used mostly as a fungicide and bactericide. The sodium salt, sodium dehydroacetate, is often used in place of dehydroacetic acid because of its greater solubility in water. It is prepared by the base-catalysed dimerization of diketene"	|	0
E266	|	"Sodium dehydroacetate"	|	"the sodium salt of propionic acid"	|	0
E266	|	"Biocide 470F"	|	E265	|	0
E266	|	"Methylacetopyronone"	|	E265	|	0
E270	|	"Lactic acid"	|	"Lactic acid, is an organic compound belonging to the family of carboxylic acids, it occurs naturally in the blood (in the form of its salts, called lactates) when, during exercise, glycogen is broken down in the muscles"	|	1
E270	|	"Milk acid"	|	E270	|	1
E280	|	"Propionic acid"	|	"Preservative which inhibits the growth of mold and some bacteria."	|	0
E280	|	"ethanecarboxylic acid"	|	E280	|	0
E280	|	"propionic acid"	|	E280	|	0
E281	|	"Sodium propionate"	|	"Typical products are flour products, where it is used as a mould inhibitor, and a means of reducing the yeast content of bread."	|	0
E281	|	"Sodium propionate"	|	E281	|	0
E281	|	"Napropion"	|	E281	|	0
E282	|	"Calcium propionate"	|	"Typically applied to flour products, where it is used as a mold inhibitor, and a means of reducing the yeast content of bread."	|	0
E282	|	"Calcium propionate"	|	E282	|	0
E282	|	"Mycoban"	|	E282	|	0
E283	|	"Potassium propionate"	|	"Typically applied to flour products, where it is used as a mold inhibitor, and a means of reducing the yeast content of bread."	|	0
E283	|	"Potassium propionate"	|	E283	|	0
E284	|	"Boric acid"	|	"Boric acid is best known for being an antiseptic, it is also used in creams and ointments, insecticides, leather finishing, paints, soaps, wood preserving, and in ceramics and glass manufacturing."	|	0
E284	|	"Orthoboric acid"	|	E284	|	0
E284	|	"Boracic acid"	|	E284	|	0
E284	|	"Sassolite"	|	E284	|	0
E284	|	"Optibor"	|	E284	|	0
E284	|	"Borofax"	|	E284	|	0
E284	|	"Trihydroxyborane"	|	E284	|	0
E285	|	"borax"	|	"An acidity regulator. Borax has many industrial uses including as an added ingredient in washing powder, water softeners and soaps. Borax is also mixed with clay and other substances to produce porcelain enamels used in pottery, and other ceramics. It is also used in the glass industry, the textile industry, in tanning leather, and in the manufacture of paper"	|	0
E285	|	"sodium borate"	|	E285	|	0
E285	|	"sodium tetraborate"	|	E285	|	0
E285	|	"disodium tetraborate"	|	E285	|	0
E290	|	"Carbon dioxide"	|	"A gas present in air, produced in combustion, fermentation and animal metabolism. Carbon dioxide is produced when any form of carbon or almost any carbon compound is burned in an excess of oxygen"	|	0
E290	|	"Carbonic acid gas"	|	E290	|	0
E290	|	"Carbonic anhydride"	|	E290	|	0
E290	|	"Carbonic oxide"	|	E290	|	0
E290	|	"Carbon oxide"	|	E290	|	0
E290	|	"Carbon(IV) oxide"	|	E290	|	0
E290	|	"Dry ice (solid phase)"	|	E290	|	0
E296	|	"Malic acid (acid)"	|	"Malic is an acidity regulator and flavoring agent, is encoded as E296 by the European Union. It is the principal acid contained in apples, apricots, peaches, plums and many other fruits and vegetables, commercially it is produced by synthesis"	|	0
E296	|	"L-Malic acid"	|	E295	|	0
E296	|	D-Malic acid"	|	E295	|	0
E296	|	"(–)-Malic acid"	|	E295	|	0
E296	|	"(+)-Malic acid"	|	E295	|	0
E296	|	"(S)-Hydroxybutanedioic acid"	|	E295	|	0
E296	|	"(R)-Hydroxybutanedioic acid"	|	E295	|	0
E297	|	"Fumaric acid"	|	"Fumaric acid is a natural acid present in many fruits and vegetables. Commercially made by fermentation of sugar by fungi or by chemical synthesis"	|	0
E297	|	"trans-1,2-Ethylenedicarboxylic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E297	|	"2-Butenedioic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E297	|	"trans-butenedioic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E297	|	"Allomaleic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E297	|	"Boletic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E297	|	"Donitic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E297	|	"Lichenic acid"	|	E297	|	0
E300 	|	"Ascorbic acid"	|	"Ascorbic acid is vitamin C; however, it cannot be added as a vitamin supplement when labelled E300. When added to foods it functions as an anti-oxidant and bread enhancer.  Ascorbic acid and ascorbates can be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. "	|	0
E300	|	"Vitamin C"	|	E300	|	0
E301 	|	"Sodium ascorbate"	|	"Sodium salt of ascorbic acid (vitamin C, a n atural acid), which occurs naturally in most fruits and vegetables. It prevents browning of fruits as well as formation of nitrosamines in meat. "	|	0
E301	|	"Sodascorbate"	|	E301	|	0
E301	|	"Monosodium ascorbate"	|	E301	|	0
E302 	|	"Calcium ascorbate"	|	"Ascorbic acid is vitamin C; however, it cannot be added as a vitamin supplement when labelled E302. It prevents browning of fruits as well as formation of nitrosamines in meat. Ascorbic acid and ascorbates can be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. "	|	0
E302	|	"Calcium diascorbate"	|	E302	|	0
E302	|	"Calcium L-ascorbate"	|	E302	|	0
E302	|	"Hemicalcium ascorbate"	|	E302	|	0
E302	|	"Calci-C"	|	E302	|	0
E303 	|	"Potassium ascorbate"	|	Although it is not a permitted food additive in the European Union or the USA, it is approved for use in Australia and New Zealand	|	4
E303	|	"Monopotassium ascorbate"	|	E303	|	4
E303	|	"Potassium L-ascorbate"	|	E303	|	4
E304 	|	"Ascorbyl palmitate"	|	"""Anti-oxidant in fatty products, especially added to prevent rancidity in
 plant oils with many unsaturated fatty acids. Also used for the food 
colours E160 and E161 to prevent oxidation of these colours."""	|	4
E304	|	"Ascorbyl palmitate"	|	E304	|	4
E304	|	"L-Ascorbic acid 6-hexadecanoate"	|	E304	|	4
E304	|	"6-O-Palmitoylascorbic acid"	|	E304	|	4
E305 	|	"Ascorbyl stearate"	|	"It is used asa source of vitamin C and as an antioxidant food additive in margarine."	|	0
E305	|	"L-Ascorbic acid"	|	E305	|	0
E305	|	"6-octadecanoate Ascorbyl monooctadecanoate"	|	E305	|	0
E306 	|	Tocopherols (natural) 	|	"Extract of vegetable oils rich in tocopherols (vitamin E). Anti-oxidant in fatty products, especially added to prevent rancidity of animal oils."	|	0
E306	|	TCP	|	E306	|	0
E307 	|	Alpha-tocopherol (synthetic) 	|	"Extract of vegetable oils rich in tocopherols (vitamin E), especially sunflower oil. Can also be made by chemical synthesis. Tocopherols can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians."	|	0
E308 	|	Gamma-tocopherol (synthetic) 	|	"Extract of vegetable oils rich in tocopherols (vitamin E), especially soybean oil. Can also be made by chemical synthesis.     Anti-oxidant in fatty products, especially added to prevent rancidity of olive oil. Rather low vitamin Eactivity. "	|	0
E309 	|	Delta-tocopherol (synthetic) 	|	 Extract of vegetable oils rich in tocopherols (vitamin E), especially soybean oil. Can also be made by chemical synthesis. Anti-oxidant in fatty products, especially added to prevent rancidity of olive oil. Rather low vitamin Eactivity. 	|	0
E310 	|	Propyl gallate 	|	"
Propyl gallate is used to protect oils and fats in products from oxidation.
It is used in foods, cosmetics, hair products, adhesives, and lubricants."	|	0
E310	|	Gallic acid	|	E310	|	0
E310	|	propyl ester	|	E310	|	0
E310	|	n-Propyl gallate	|	E310	|	0
E311 	|	Octyl gallate 	|	Synthesised from octanol and gallic acid, which is produced from plant tannins. This antioxidant is used in numerous cosmetics and pharmaceutical, 
cosmetic, and food products such as soaps, shampoos, shaving soaps, skin.
 lotions, deodorants, margarine, and peanut butter.	|	0
E311	|	 Progallin O	|	E311	|	0
E311	|	n-Ocyl gallate	|	E311	|	0
E311	|	Stabilizer GA-8	|	E311	|	0
E311	|	Gallic acid octyl ester	|	E311	|	0
E312 	|	Dodecyl gallate 	|	 Synthesised from lauryl alcohol and gallic acid, which is produced from plant tannins.  As a food additive it is used as an antioxidant and preservative.	|	0
E312	|	Lauryl gallate	|	E312	|	0
E313 	|	Ethyl gallate 	|	 Synthetic anti-oxidant. Anti-oxidant in fatty products, especially added to prevent rancidity. 	|	0
E313	|	Phyllemblin	|	E313	|	0
E313	|	 gallic acid ethyl ester	|	E313	|	0
E314 	|	Guaiac resin 	|	Natural resin from the tree Guajacum officinale  and some related tropical trees. Anti-oxidant in cola.  314 can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. 
    	|	0
E314	|	Guaiacum	|	E314	|	0
E315 	|	Erythorbic acid 	|	 Anti-oxidant. Synthetic isomer of vitamin C, but with only 1/20 of the vitamin activity. It is also used as a preservative in cured meats and frozen vegetables. Erythorbic acid and erythorbates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E315	|	D-Araboascorbic acid	|	E315	|	0
E315	|	Erythorbate	|	E315	|	0
E315	|	Isoascorbic acid	|	E315	|	0
E316 	|	Sodium erythorbate 	|	Sodium erythorbate is a food additive used predominantly in meats, poultry, and soft drinks. Sodium erythorbate is produced from sugars derived from different sources, such as beets, sugar cane, and corn. 	|	0
E316	|	D-Isoascorbate	|	E316	|	0
E316	|	Erythorbic acid	|	E316	|	0
E316	|	sodium salt	|	E316	|	0
E317 	|	Erythorbin acid 	|	It is a vegetable-derived food additive produced from sucrose. It is also used as a preservative in cured meats and frozen vegetables.	|	0
E318 	|	Sodium erythorbin 	|	Calcium erythorbate is a food additive. As an antioxidant structurally related to vitamin C, it helps improve flavor stability and prevents the formation of carcinogenic nitrosamines.	|	0
E319 	|	Butylhydroxinon 	|	Anti-oxidant in oils. In foods, it is used as a preservative for unsaturated vegetable oils and many edible animal fats. E319 can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. 	|	0
E319	|	TBHQ	|	E319	|	0
E320 	|	Butylated hydroxyanisole (BHA) 	|	Anti-oxidant in fats and fatty products to prevent rancidity. The primary use for BHA is as an antioxidant and preservative in food, 
food packaging, animal feed, cosmetics, rubber, and petroleum products.	|	0
E320	|	Antioxyne B	|	E320	|	0
E320	|	BOA	|	E320	|	0
E321 	|	Butylated hydroxytoluene (BHT) 	|	 Anti-oxidant in fats and fatty products to prevent rancidity. E321 can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. 	|	0
E321	|	AO-29	|	E321	|	0
E321	|	 Avox BHT	|	E321	|	0
E321	|	 Additin RC 7110	|	E321	|	0
E322 	|	Lecithin 	|	Emulsifier commercially produced from soybeans or egg yolks.	|	3
E323 	|	Anoxomer 	|	It is a non-digestible polymeric antioxidant	|	
E324 	|	Ethoxyquin 	|	It is commonly used as a preservative in pet foods to prevent the rancidification of fats. Ethoxyquin is also commonly used in spices to prevent color loss due to oxidation of the natural carotenoid pigments 	|	
E325 	|	Sodium lactate 	|	It is produced by fermentation of a sugar source, such as corn or beets. It is used in cheese, confectionary, icecream, fruit jellies, soups, canned fruits. Should not be given to babies. and small children	|	0
E325	|	Sodium DL-lactate	|	E325	|	0
E325	|	 Lactic acid sodium salt	|	E325	|	0
E326 	|	Potassium lactate	|	It is used as preservatives, mainly against yeasts and fungi. It is also used 
to increase stability of anti-oxidants and to prevent drying of 
different products. Can be found in cheese, confectionary, icecream, fruit jellies, soups, canned fruits. Should not be given to babies and small children.	|	0
E327 	|	Calcium lactate 	|	It is used as preservatives, mainly against yeasts and fungi.  It is mainly used to stabilize the structure of fruits, vegetables and 
potatoes during processing. It also has anti-oxidant activity. Should not be given to babies and small children.	|	0
E327	|	calcium lactate 5-hydrate,	|	E327	|	0
E327	|	 calcium lactate,	|	E327	|	0
E327	|	 2-hydroxypropanoic acid	|	E327	|	0
E327	|	 calcium salt pentahydrate	|	E327	|	0
E328 	|	Ammonium lactate 	|	It is used as preservatives, mainly against yeasts and fungi. Lactic acid is found primarily in sour milk products, such as koumiss, laban, yogurt, kefir, and some cottage cheeses. 	|	1
E328	|	Lactic acid	|	E328	|	1
E328	|	Milk acid	|	E328	|	1
E329 	|	Magnesium lactate 	|	It is a salt of lactic acid and it is used as a mineral supplement.	|	0
E330 	|	Citric acid 	|	It is mainly used as an acidity regulator as well as aroma compound. It increases gel strength in marmalades and decreases enzymatic browning 
in fruits and fruit products. Citric acid and citrates can normally be consumed by all 
religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. Citric acid does not cause 
allergic reactions in people who are allergic to oranges and citrus 
fruits, as it is commercially made from sugar, not fruits.	|	0
E331 	|	Sodium citrates 	|	 Citric acid and citrates have many functions – they increase the activity of many antioxidants, and exhibit some antioxidant activity. They are mainly used as acidity regulators as well as aroma compounds. They increase gel strength in marmalades and decrease enzymatic browning in fruits and fruit products. Citric acid and citrates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E331	|	Monosodium citrate	|	E331	|	0
E331	|	Disodium citrate	|	E331	|	0
E331	|	Sodium citrate	|	E331	|	0
E332 	|	Potassium citrates	|	 Citric acid and citrates have many functions – they increase the activity of many antioxidants, and exhibit some antioxidant activity. Potassium citrate is used as a buffer, to bind metal ions and as a nutrient source for yeasts in special fermented products. They increase gel strength in marmalades and decrease enzymatic browning in fruits and fruit products. Citric acid and citrates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E332	|	Monopotassium citrate	|	E332	|	0
E332	|	Potassium citrate	|	E332	|	0
E333 	|	Calcium citrates	|	Calcium citrate is used as a buffer, to bind metal ions and to improve the texture of canned vegetables. Citric acid and citrates can normally be consumed by all 
religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. Citric acid does not cause 
allergic reactions in people who are allergic to oranges and other 
citrus fruits, as it is commercially made from sugar, not fruits.	|	0
E333	|	Monocalcium citrate	|	E333	|	0
E333	|	Dicalcium citrate	|	E333	|	0
E333	|	Calcium citrate	|	E333	|	0
E334 	|	Tartaric acid	|	 Natural acid, present in many fruits, especially grapes. Commercially prepared from waste products of the wine industry (grape skins). Tartaric acid and tartarates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E334	|	2,3-dihydroxysuccinic acid	|	E334	|	0
E334	|	 threaric acid	|	E334	|	0
E334	|	 racemic acid	|	E334	|	0
E334	|	 uvic acid	|	E334	|	0
E334	|	 paratartaric acid	|	E334	|	0
E335 	|	Sodium tartrates	|	Sodium salts of tartaric acid, a natural acid present in many fruits, especially grapes. Commercially prepared from waste products of the wine industry (grape skins). 
    Tartaric acid and tartarates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E335	|	Monosodium tartrate	|	E335	|	0
E335	|	Disodium tartrate 	|	E335	|	0
E336 	|	Potassium tartrates	|	Potassium salts of tartaric acid, a natural acid present in many fruits, especially grapes. Commercially prepared from waste products of the wine industry (grape skins). 
    Tartaric acid and tartarates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E336	|	Monopotassium tartrate	|	E336	|	0
E336	|	Dipotassium tartrate 	|	E336	|	0
E336	|	Argol	|	E336	|	0
E337 	|	Sodium potassium tartrate 	|	Potassium salts of tartaric acid, a natural acid present in many fruits, especially grapes. Commercially prepared from waste products of the wine industry (grape skins). 
    Tartaric acid and tartarates can normally be consumed by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E338 	|	Orthophosphoric acid 	|	Normal constituent of many fruits and vegetables. Commercially produced from phosphate mined in the US. Phosphoric acid and phosphates can normally be consumed by 
all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. Although animal bones are 
mainly made up of phosphates, commercial phosphate is not made from 
bones.	|	0
E338	|	Phosphoric acid 	|	E338	|	0
E338	|	phosphoric(V) acid	|	E338	|	0
E339 	|	Sodium phosphates	|	Sodium salts of phosphoric acid. Normal constituent of the body. Commercially produced from phosphoric acid, which is produced from phosphate mined in the US. Phosphoric acid and phosphates can normally be consumed by 
all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. Although animal bones are 
mainly made up of phosphates, commercial phosphate is not made from 
bones.	|	0
E339	|	Monosodium phosphate	|	E339	|	0
E339	|	Disodium phosphate	|	E339	|	0
E339	|	Trisodium phosphate 	|	E339	|	0
E340 	|	Potassium phosphates	|	Sodium salts of phosphoric acid. Normal constituent of the body. Commercially produced from phosphoric acid, which is produced from phosphate mined in the US. Phosphoric acid and phosphates can normally be consumed by 
all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. Although animal bones are 
mainly made up of phosphates, commercial phosphate is not made from 
bones.	|	0
E340	|	Monopotassium phosphate	|	E340	|	0
E340	|	Dipotassium phosphate	|	E340	|	0
E340	|	Tripotassium phosphate 	|	E340	|	0
E341 	|	Calcium phosphates	|	Calcium phosphate is an acidity regulator, used in baking powder and acts as a bread enhancer. Phosphoric acid and phosphates can normally be consumed by all religious
 groups, vegans and vegetarians. Although animal bones are mainly made 
up of phosphates, commercial phosphate is not made from bones.	|	0
E341	|	Monocalcium phosphate	|	E341	|	0
E341	|	Dicalcium phosphate	|	E341	|	0
E341	|	Tricalcium phosphate 	|	E341	|	0
E342 	|	Ammonium phosphates	|	Ammonium phosphate is the salt of ammonia and phosphoric acid. Ammonium phosphate is used as an ingredient in some fertilizers as a source of nitrogen. It is also used in bread making to promote the growth of the yeast.	|	0
E342	|	Ammonium polyphosphate	|	E342	|	0
E342	|	Monoammonium phosphate	|	E342	|	0
E342	|	Diammonium phosphate	|	E342	|	0
E342	|	triammonium phosphate	|	E342	|	0
E343 	|	Magnesium phosphates 	|	Magnesium phosphate is used as an emulsifier; it also increases the activity of antioxidants. It prevents clumping in powders. Phosphoric acid and phosphates can normally be consumed by all religious
 groups, vegans and vegetarians. Although animal bones are mainly made 
up of phosphates, commercial phosphate is not made from bones.	|	0
E343	|	Dimagnesium phosphate	|	E343	|	0
E343	|	Magnesium phosphate tribasic	|	E343	|	0
E344 	|	Lecitin citrate 	|	 Lecithin is the emulsifier that keeps cocoa and cocoa butter in a candy bar from separating. Lecithin is approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration for human consumption with the status generally recognized as safe.	|	0
E345 	|	Magnesium citrate 	|	Magnesium citrate is  a mixture of magnesium carbonate and citric acid. 
It’s predominantly a  dietary supplement used primarily for the 
treatment of magnesium deficiency. Magnesium citrate works by attracting water through the tissues by a process known as osmosis.	|	0
E345	|	Magnesium	|	E345	|	0
E349 	|	Ammonium malate 	|	Ammonium malate is an acidity regulator. It is banned in The EU. 	|	0
E349	|	Ammonium hydroxybutanedioate	|	E349	|	0
E350 	|	Sodium malates	|	Sodium malate is a natural acid present in fruit. Sodium malate is used as a buffer and flavouring. Can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E350	|	Sodium malate	|	E350	|	0
E350	|	Sodium hydrogen malate 	|	E350	|	0
E351 	|	Potassium malate 	|	Acts as an antioxidant and as a food flavor. Can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E352 	|	Calcium malates 	|	It is a natural acid present in fruits. Calcium malate is used as a thickener and flavouring. 	|	0
E352	|	Calcium malate	|	E352	|	0
E352	|	Calcium hydrogen malate	|	E352	|	0
E353 	|	Metatartaric acid 	|	 Acid, present in sugar cane and produced from glucose. Can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E354 	|	Calcium tartrate 	|	It is an acidity regulator and preservative. Tartaric acid and tartarates can be used by all vegans and vegetarians. 	|	0
E355 	|	Adipic acid 	|	Natural acid present in beets and sugar cane (juice). Adipic acid and adipates can be used by all vegans and vegetarians. 	|	0
E355	|	hexanedioic acid	|	E355	|	0
E356 	|	Sodium adipate 	|	 Sodium salt of adipic acid, a natural acid present in beets and sugar cane (juice). Adipic acid and adipates can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E356	|	Disodium adipate	|	E356	|	0
E357 	|	Potassium adipate 	|	 Potassium salt of adipic acid, a natural acid present in beets and sugar cane (juice). Adipic acid and adipates can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E359 	|	Ammonium adipate 	|	It is a salt of adipic acid.	|	0
E359	|	Ammonium hexanedioate	|	E359	|	0
E363 	|	Succinic acid 	|	 Natural acid, present in most fruits and vegetables. Commercially synthesised from acetic acid. Can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians. 	|	0
E365 	|	Sodium fumarate 	|	It is natural acid in cells. You can find it in bakery products, baking powder, etc. 	|	0
E365	|	Disodium fumarate	|	E365	|	0
E366 	|	Potassium fumarate 	|	It is natural acid in cells. You can find it in bakery products, baking powder, etc. 	|	0
E366	|	potassium (E)-butenedioate	|	E366	|	0
E366	|	Dipotassium fumarate	|	E366	|	0
E366	|	Fumaric acid	|	E366	|	0
E367 	|	Calcium fumarate 	|	It reduces the sugar needed in products.	|	0
E367	|	trans-1,2-Ethylenedicarboxylic acid	|	E367	|	0
E367	|	 2-Butenedioic acid	|	E367	|	0
E367	|	trans-butenedioic acid	|	E367	|	0
E367	|	 Allomaleic acid	|	E367	|	0
E367	|	 Boletic acid	|	E367	|	0
E367	|	 Donitic acid	|	E367	|	0
E367	|	 Lichenic acid	|	E367	|	0
E368 	|	Ammonium fumarate 	|	It is acidity regulator.  It is a salt of fumaric acid.	|	0
E368	|	Diammonium fumarate	|	E368	|	0
E370 	|	1,4-Heptonolactone 	|	 It is a synthetic product, prepared from hydroxy-heptanoic acid. It is used as acidity regulator and flavouring. 	|	0
E380 	|	Triammonium citrate 	|		|	0
E381 	|	Ammonium ferric citrate 	|	It is a green or reddish-brown powder and it is used as an acidity regulator. It is used in chocolate confectionery, cheese spreads, etc. E381 is a normal component of all body cells. 	|	0
E381	|	Ferric ammonium citrate	|	E381	|	0
E381	|	Ammonium Iron(III) Citrate	|	E381	|	0
E381	|	Prothoate+	|	E381	|	0
E381	|	Iron ammonium citrate	|	E381	|	0
E383 	|	Calcium glycerylphosphate 	|		|	0
E384 	|	Isopropyl citrate 	|		|	0
E385 	|	Calcium disodium ethylene diamine tetraacetate, (Calcium disodium EDTA) 	|		|	0
E385	|	Diaminoethane-tetraacetic acid	|	E385	|	0
E385	|	Edetic acid	|	E385	|	0
E385	|	Ethylenedinitrilo-tetraacetic acid	|	E385	|	0
E385	|	Versene	|	E385	|	0
E386 	|	Disodium ethylene diamine tetraacetate (Disodium EDTA) 	|	A sequestrant is a term for a food additive. Sequestrants improve the quality and stability of the food products.	|	0
E387 	|	Oxystearin 	|		|	4
E388 	|	Thiodipropionic acid 	|	Antioxidant. Mainly used in cosmetics, but also in oils and fats. Can be used by all religious groups, vegans and vegetarians.  	|	0
E389 	|	Dilauryl thiodipropionate 	|		|	0
E390 	|	Distearyl thiodipropionate 	|		|	0
E391 	|	Phytic acid 	|	Inositol or its phosphates and associated lipids are found in many foods, in particular fruit	|	0
E391	|	inositol 	|	E391	|	0
E392 	|	Extracts of rosemary 	|	Rosmarinus officinalis, commonly known as rosemary, is a woody, perennial herb with fragrant, evergreen, needle-like leaves and white, pink, purple, or blue flowers, native to the Mediterranean region.	|	0
E399 	|	Calcium lactobionate 	|	It is a sugar acid. Calcium lactobionate is a food additive used as a stabilizer. 	|	0
E399	|	Galactosylgluconic acid	|	E399	|	0
E441	|	Gelatine	|	An animal-derived protein used as a thickener in fruit jels, candies and marshmallows; as a coating on medicines, and in cosmetics.	|	4
E542	|	Edible Bone Phosphate	|		|	4
E631	|	Sodium 5′-Inosinate – Glutamic Acid	|		|	4
E901	|	Beeswax, white and yellow	|		|	4
E904	|	Shellac – Resin from Lac Bug	|		|	4
E910	|	L-cysteine	|		|	4
E913	|	Lanolin, sheep wool grease	|		|	4
E920	|	 L-cysteine	|		|	4
E921	|	 L-cysteine	|		|	4
E966	|	Lactitol	|		|	4
E400	|	Alginic acid 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E401	|	Sodium alginate 	|	Antioxidant. It is used in baking jams and confections. E401 can be used by vegans and vegetarians.	|	0
E402	|	Potassium alginate 	|	Antioxidant. As a food additive is is used as thickening agent and emulsifier. 	|	0
E403	|	Ammonium alginate 	|	Antioxidant. As a food additive is is used as thickening agent and emulsifier. 	|	0
E404	|	Calcium alginate 	|	Antioxidant. As a food additive is is used as thickening agent and emulsifier. 	|	0
E405	|	Propane-1, 2-diol alginate 	|	Antioxidant. As a food additive is is used as thickening agent and emulsifier. 	|	0
E406	|	Agar 	|	Antioxidant. It is used as a thickening agent and stabiliser. 	|	0
E407	|	Carrageenan 	|	Antioxidant. It is used as a thickening agent and stabiliser in food. 	|	0
E407a	|		|	Antioxidant	|	0
E410	|	Locust bean gum 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E412	|	Guar Gum 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E413	|	Tragacanth	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E414	|	Gum Arabic 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E415	|	Xanthan gum 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E416	|	Karaya gum 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E417	|	Tara gum 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E418	|	Gellan gum 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E420	|	Sorbitol	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E421	|	Mannitol	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E425	|	Konjac gum	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E450	|	Di- and polyphosphates 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E451	|	Triphosphates 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E452	|	Polyphosphates 	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E459	|	Beta-cyclodextrine	|	Antioxidant	|	0
E460	|	Cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Cellulose is the main polysaccharide and constituent of wood and all plant structures. Commercially prepared from wood. 	|	0
E461	|	Methyl cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Prepared from cellulose. Used as thickening agent, filler, dietary fibre, anti clumping agent and emulsfier. 	|	0
E462	|	Ethyl cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Prepared from cellulose. Used as thickening agent, filler, dietary fibre, anti clumping agent and emulsfier. Few products, and no longer permitted as emulsifier in the EU. 	|	0
E463	|	Hydroxypropyl cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Prepared from cellulose. Used as thickening agent, filler, dietary fibre, anti clumping agent and emulsfier. 	|	0
E464	|	Hydroxypropylmethyl cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Prepared from cellulose. Used as thickening agent, filler, dietary fibre, anti clumping agent and emulsfier. 	|	0
E465	|	Methylethyl cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Methylethylcellulose is prepared from cellulose. Commercially prepared from wood and chemically modified. Used as thickening agent, filler, dietary fibre, anti clumping agent and emulsfier. 	|	0
E466	|	Carboxymethyl cellulose 	|	Antioxidant. Carboxymethylcellulose is prepared from cellulose. Used as thickening agent, filler, dietary fibre, anti clumping agent and emulsfier. 	|	0
E468	|	Crosslinked sodium carboxymethyl cellulose	|	Antioxidant. 	|	0
E469	|	Sodium caseinate	|	Antioxidant. Emulsifier, mineral salt made from casein in cow's milk for thickener and
 beverage whitener, dessert mixes, reduced cream whip.	|	1
		Casein	|	Sodium Caseinate	|	1
		Rennet	|	Coagulant derived from calves stomachs and used in cheesemaking.	|	4
		Rennin	|	Rennet	|	Rennet
		Whey	|	A milk by-product.	|	1
		Mayonnaise	|	Usually a blend of eggs and oil.	|	2
		Albumen	|	Egg whites	|	2
		Albumin	|	Albumen	|	
		Lard	|	Animal-derived shortening or fat	|	4
		Suet	|	Animal-derived shortening or fat	|	4
		Isinglass	|	Gelatin (animal-protein) derived from fish.	|	4
		Lactose	|	Milk Sugar	|	1
		Pepsin	|	Enzyme derived from the stomach of pigs.	|	4
		Tallow	|	Solid fat derived from sheep and cattle.	|	4